wavesplatform.com 2018-10-03

# Privacy policy

Privacy policy
INTRODUCTION
Welcome to the WavesPlatform AG’s privacy notice.
Waves Platform AG respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy
notice will inform you as to how we look after your personal data when you visit our website
https://wavesplatform.com/ or its subdomains (collectively “Website”) and tell you about your privacy rights and
how the law protects you.
1. IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND WHO WE ARE
PURPOSE OF THIS PRIVACY NOTICE
This privacy notice aims to give you information on how Waves Platform AG collects and processes your
personal data through your use of this website, including any data you may provide through this Website when
you sign up to our newsletters or communicate with our support service.
This Website is not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.
It is important that you read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice
we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you so that
you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements the other notices
and is not intended to override them.
Waves Platform AG is responsible for your personal data (collectively referred to as “we”, “us” or “our” in this
privacy notice). Our office is situated at Dammstrasse 16, 6300 Zug, Switzerland.
You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Federal Data Protection and Information
Commissioner        (FDPIC),      the   Swiss     supervisory    authority    for   data      protection   issues
(https://www.edoeb.admin.ch/edoeb/en/home.html). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with
your concerns before you approach the FDPIC so please contact us in the first instance.
CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY NOTICE AND YOUR DUTY TO INFORM US OF CHANGES
This version was last updated on 09/07/2018.
It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if
your personal data changes during your relationship with us.
THIRD-PARTY LINKS
This Website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or
enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these
third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our Website, we
encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.
2. THE DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU
Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can
be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped
together as follows:
Information You Give Us: We receive and store any information you enter on our Website or give us in any
other way. You provide most such information when you search some information on our Website, subscribe
to our newsletters, fill out a form for any media, events or partnership inquiries, communicate with our support
service. For example, you provide information when you communicate with us by post, e-mail, or otherwise.
As a result of those actions, you might supply us with such information as your name, address, e-mail, phone
numbers, etc.
Automatic Information: We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. For
example, like many websites, we use "cookies," and we obtain certain types of information when your Web
browser accesses our Website.
Information from Other Sources: We might receive information about you from other sources and add it to
our account information.
We also collect, use and share Aggregated Data such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose.
However, Aggregated Data is not considered personal data as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal
your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing
a specific website feature.
We do not collect any Special Categories of Personal Data about you (this includes details about your race
or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union
membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information
about criminal convictions and offences.
3. HOW IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA COLLECTED?
We use different methods to collect data from and about you. We will collect and process the following data
about you:
Information you give us. This is information about you that you give us by filling the forms or by corresponding
with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:
        •   subscribe to our publications or newsletters; or
        •   enter a competition, promotional action or survey; or
        •   give us some feedback; or
        •   communicate with our support services; or
        •   do any other actions through our Website.
Automated technologies or interactions. As you interact with our website, we may automatically collect
Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using
cookies, server logs and other similar technologies. Please see our Cookie policy for further details.
Third parties or publicly available sources. We may receive personal data about you from various third
parties and public sources as set out below:
        •   Technical Data from the following parties:
       (a) analytics providers such as Google based outside the EU;
       (b) advertising networks; and
       (c) search information providers.

4. HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA
We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data
in the following circumstances:
  •    Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and
       fundamental rights do not override those interests.
  •    Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.
If you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more
than one ground has been set out in the table below.
 Purpose/Activity                    Type of data                 Lawful basis for processing including
                                                                  basis of legitimate interest
 To manage our relationship with (a) Identity                     (a) Necessary to comply with a legal
 you which will include:                                          obligation
 (a) Notifying you about changes (b) Contact
      to our terms or privacy policy
 (b) Providing technical support
 To enable you to partake in a       (a) Identity                 (a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to
 prize draw, competition,                                         study how users use our services, to develop
 promotional activity or complete    (b) Contact                  them and grow our business)
 a survey
                                     (с) Usage
                                     (d) Marketing and
                                     Communications
 To administer and protect our       (a) Technical                (a) Necessary for our legitimate interests
 business and the Website                                         (for running our business, provision of
 (including troubleshooting, data                                 administration and IT services, network
 analysis, testing, system                                        security, to prevent fraud)
 maintenance, support, reporting
 and hosting of data)                                             (b) Necessary to comply with a legal
                                                                  obligation
 To deliver relevant        website (a) Usage                     Necessary for our legitimate interests (to
 content to you                                                   study how users use our services, to
                                     (b) Marketing and            develop them, to grow our business and to
                                     Communications               inform our marketing strategy)
                                     (c)   Technical

 To use data analytics to improve (a) Technical                   Necessary for our legitimate interests (to
 our website, services,                                           define types of customers for our services, to
 marketing, customer                 (b) Usage                    keep our Website updated and relevant, to
 relationships and experiences                                    develop our business and to inform our
                                                                  marketing strategy)
 To discuss possible partnership     (a) Identity                 Necessary for our legitimate interests (to
 and marketing cooperation                                        promote our products and services)
                                     (b) Contact
                                     (c) Marketing and
                                     Communications
COOKIES
You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access
cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible
or not function properly. For more information about the cookies we use, please see Cookie Policy.
CHANGE OF PURPOSE
We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider
that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish
to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose,
please contact us via e-mail support@wavesplatform.com.
If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal
basis which allows us to do so.
Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with
the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.
5. DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA
We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table
in paragraph 4 above.
     •   Third Parties who developed the Website and organize promotional and marketing activities.
     •   Third Parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets.
         Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to
         our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this
         privacy notice.
We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the
law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and
only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

6. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS
We share your personal data with our contractors to fulfil the purposes we collected it for. This will involve
transferring your data outside the European Economic Area (EEA), namely to the Russian Federation and the
United States.
These countries may have less stringent privacy laws than we do, so any information they hold can become
subject to their laws and disclosure requirements, including disclosure to governmental bodies, regulatory
agencies and private persons. In addition, a number of countries have agreements under which information is
exchanged with other countries for law enforcement, tax and other purposes.
However, we ensure your personal data is protected by requiring all our contractors to follow the same rules
when processing your personal data.
Please contact us via e-mail support@wavesplatform.com if you want further information on the specific
mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA.
7. DATA SECURITY
We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost,
used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal
data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They
will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.
We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any
applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so. The transmission of data over the
internet (including by e-mail) is never completely secure. So, although we use appropriate measures to try to
protect personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of data transmitted to us or by us.
8. DATA RETENTION
HOW LONG WILL YOU USE MY PERSONAL DATA FOR?
We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including
for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.
In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data (Request erasure).
In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with
you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further
notice to you.
9. YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS
Under certain circumstances, you have the following rights under data protection laws in relation to your
personal data:
  •   Request access to your personal data.
  •   Request correction of your personal data.
  •   Request erasure of your personal data.
  •   Object to processing of your personal data.
  •   Request restriction of processing your personal data.
  •   Request transfer of your personal data.

  •   Right to withdraw consent.
If you wish to exercise any            of  the  rights   set   out  above,   please   contact   us   via e-mail
support@wavesplatform.com.
NO FEE USUALLY REQUIRED
You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights).
Request the transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party
you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this
right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used
the information to perform a contract with you.
Withdraw consent at any time where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this
will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw
your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is
the case at the time you withdraw your consent. Please note that in certain circumstances it may be still lawful
for us to continue processing your information even where you have withdrawn your consent, if one of the
other legal bases is applicable.
